uh here's another question all right so
I have a question let's say you need to
review a lot of material while you're
searching for a job and there's a window
where you need to put these materials on
your
resumé and you're still learning
them what would you recommend to do in
this scenario do you put them on your
rum or
not um the short answer is yes put them
on your risim me um and the way that you
put them on your resum is really key
right I mean the short answer for how to
what to put on your rum is to put
authentic things on your rais don't pad
your rais but don't undersell yourself
and we'll talk about this when we talk
about raises in general uh the risim is
the primary instrument of trust with one
sole purpose get an interview that means
don't give up too much information on
your resume your r is supposed to troll
them it's supposed to tease them right
it's supposed to get them to want to
talk to you more it's like oh my God
that sounds so amazing but I want to
know more how am I ever going to know
more now we'll talk about that's a whole
separate video about rais I'll probably
repeat it again the the ra the reason
the raim is unless you're a very
experienced person you got a CV
curriculum V you you're not it's not an
exhaustive list of everything you've
ever done the the goal of the resum is
to get an interview and or to get past
HR because you've already got the
interview because you made a a
professional network connection and they
want you to interview and they'll say
you just need to submit a rum to HR to
get past that
requirement right but if if you're so
again the ra but the risim is like damn
I got to hear more about this this
person you know why do they have this
thing on there so based on that and when
you ask the question well should you put
the technologies that you want to learn
on there my answer is yes right
and you can put that however you want I
I don't have a strong opinion about how
you do that um I personally think having
a small section saying actively pursuing
or actively learning or you know under
your education SE section there's some
debate about whether you should have an
education section at all but under the
education section I would put actively
pursuing certification in kubernetes
actively
seeking blah blah blah under your
education section if you're enrolled in
a course which some people put more
Credence in than other things I don't
then you know that kind of thing um and
it doesn't it's not lying to say that
you're actively
pursuing uh Mastery of cyber security
you know as specific as you can get
pentesting
blue the more precise the better in
General on your rume and so if you put a
bullet point or a line item in your educ
ation section that says that you are
actively pursuing your mcsc
certification you haven't got it yet
that shows that you have got the
commitment you that shows that you have
I mean if they ask you about it you can
say yeah I'm paying for this out of my
own money because I believe in staying
current I mean it just makes you look
awesome right because you're you're
going to be able to to to talk about why
you think that this is the right thing
and that goes back to another video I
made already about knowing what you want
to do down to the precise job
if you know you shouldn't even embark on
your Tech Career Journey without knowing
what tech job you are training for and
I've covered this in lots of videos go
to skill skills. you can go look at the
outline but if you haven't got that
answered you need to back up you need to
back up because you could be potentially
wasting time like I did so I have a
story about this I'm going give you a
quick story about this so I in 2020 I
thought I wanted to change career I
wanted to be in cyber security I started
going down that that path I i' made a
hard autodidactic plan I'm going to go
get the ocp I waited against all the
other shts that I wanted to get at wwg I
did all the research all the time I
started streaming about it got really
popular had like four or 500 people on
average because they wanted to learn all
hacking and they thought I was some sort
of crazy ass
hacker but they were all disappointed
when they learned and then I stopped
because the more I got into it the more
I realized the hacking was not about
breaking I've talked about this in other
videos but I learned that it wasn't
about breaking into things that's pen
testing and Bug Bounty which you can do
without having it be your career um but
what I really wanted to do was
operations and you know with a security
focus and if you watch my get up action
videos recently you'll see why you know
like like you know
publishing artifacts overo station like
that you security applies to all the
things so the bottom line I realized I
didn't want to do cyber security analyst
I wanted to be an infrastructure
engineer which I kind of already was
just wanted do that better and have this
be a security focus and so I stayed on
that path um and you know when I was
hired and this is this is this is
relevant to the risim question so when I
was hired I had zero experience for
kubernetes and I was hired as a
kubernetes engineer and they knew that I
was going to be able to learn it and one
of the things on my rume was pursuing
kubernetes I I said you know actively
maintain a kubernetes lab at home
working on building a kubernetes lab at
home and you if you want to put that
under a project section which I think is
a strong thing to do I particularly in
technology in technology having a
projects section that has your current
active projects both professionally uh
nonprofit uh or even on the job I think
you should make because the whole point
again is to get you in the door and they
want to you want to wow them and under
your project section is where your
passion projects are going to be and if
you don't have a place to put your
passion project and a lot of your
passion projects are going to be such as
building your own lab kubernetes cluster
at home that passion project is also
going to be doing double duty to teach
you how to do it by knowing how to set
up a cni you know uh or set up your own
storage classes and things like that
that you cannot do in the cloud by being
able to articulate why you're doing that
in your own home lab in an interview and
even put a bullet point so they'll ask
about it in the resum uh and you on your
resum so they ask about it
I think that's the way to go so a
project section saying you education if
it's more formal like pursuing as you
blah blah BL blah and and under uh under
the project section is say uh building
uh building kuties lab to better
understand Hardware noid deployment look
at that look at that right so that's
like that's like a line item on your
projects it shows dedication to doing
things to learning on your own and it
shows that you're willing to literally
put your money where your mouth is by
building out a lab in your own house
that you can then use indirectly as an
asset for the
company oky doie